<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Our World in Data</title>
<subtitle>Research and data to make progress against the world’s largest problems</subtitle>
<id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/</id>
<link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com"/>
<link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/atom.xml"/>
<updated>2019-10-04T08:50:13.000Z</updated>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Where in the world do people emit the most CO2?]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/per-capita-co2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/per-capita-co2"/>
    <published>2019-10-04T08:50:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-04T09:15:55.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[There are large inequalities in the carbon footprint of people across the world. How do countries across the world compare? Where in the world do people emit the most CO2?]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Who emits the most CO2 today?]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/annual-co2-emissions</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/annual-co2-emissions"/>
    <published>2019-10-03T09:45:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-04T13:20:21.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[Which countries emit the most CO2 today? How do annual emissions vary across the world?]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Who has contributed most to global CO2 emissions?]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/contributed-most-global-co2</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/contributed-most-global-co2"/>
    <published>2019-10-01T16:00:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-05T12:06:26.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[There’s not only significant variability in how much CO2 countries emit across the world today. There are also large differences in how much each has emitted in the past. Who has contributed most to global CO2 since 1750?]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The history of Our World in Data]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/our-world-in-data-history</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/our-world-in-data-history"/>
    <published>2019-09-26T17:26:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-28T08:51:44.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Max Roser</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[Our World in Data has been a project many years in the making. Here we detail the history of how the project got started, its evolution over the years and where we are today as a team.]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[12 key metrics to understand the state of the world]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/12-key-metrics</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/12-key-metrics"/>
    <published>2019-09-26T10:00:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-02T18:18:05.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[At Our World in Data we present data and research – across more than 3000 charts – on the world’s largest problems. But some metrics are core to our work: here we present 12 that are key to understanding the state of the world.]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Where does our plastic accumulate in the ocean and what does that mean for the future?]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/where-does-plastic-accumulate</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/where-does-plastic-accumulate"/>
    <published>2019-09-24T09:00:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-25T21:37:25.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[An estimated 8 million tonnes of plastic enter our oceans each year. But the plastic we find in our surface waters is more than 100-fold lower. This is the ‘missing plastic’ problem. So, where does our plastic accumulate in the ocean and what does this mean for the future?]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[If we can make maternal deaths as rare as they are in the healthiest countries we can save almost 300,000 mothers each year]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/saving-maternal-lives</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/saving-maternal-lives"/>
    <published>2019-09-20T10:55:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-20T11:13:00.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[Maternal mortality was much more common in the past. Today, the number of women that die in childbirth is much lower, but there are still large inequalities across the world. If we can make maternal deaths as rare as they are in the healthiest countries we can save almost 300,000 mothers each year.]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Talent is everywhere, opportunity is not. We are all losing out because of this.]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/talent-is-everywhere-opportunity-is-not</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/talent-is-everywhere-opportunity-is-not"/>
    <published>2019-09-19T10:53:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-19T18:37:43.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Max Roser</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[The world needs ideas and innovation to make progress against the many problems we face. Creative and talented people that can contribute to this important work are everywhere, but the opportunity to develop is limited to only a small number of well-off children. As a consequence of this, we all – the entire world population – are missing out on the creativity and innovations that would enrich our world and help us move forward.]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[The rise of social media]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/rise-of-social-media</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/rise-of-social-media"/>
    <published>2019-09-18T10:00:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-20T08:49:08.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Esteban Ortiz-Ospina</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[Social media sites are used by more than two-thirds of all internet users. When did the rise of social media start and what are the largest sites today? ]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Where are women most at risk of dying in childbirth?]]></title>
    <id>https://staging-owid.netlify.com/risk-of-dying-in-childbirth</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://staging-owid.netlify.com/risk-of-dying-in-childbirth"/>
    <published>2019-09-17T09:34:36.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-09-27T14:37:47.000Z</updated>
    <author><name>Hannah Ritchie</name></author>
    <summary><![CDATA[Pregnancy and childbirth are much safer for women today than in the past. But maternal mortality rates are still high in many countries in the world. A woman is 300 to 400 times more likely to die per pregnancy in poor countries than in rich.]]></summary>
</entry>
</feed>
